Guide to the Joseph St. Leger d'Happart Papers, 1768-1815 DAR.1957.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Personal Papers, 1800-1812; VI.
  - Thompson family papers, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Personal Accounts, 1800 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Personal Accounts, 1800 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Maria Read to d'Happart, 1800-1812 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Maria Read to d'Happart, 1800-1812 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Maria Read to d'Happart, 1800-1812 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Elizabeth Thompson St. Leger d'Happart to d'Happart, 1803-1805 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth Thompson St. Leger d'Happart to d'Happart, 1803-1805 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Elizabeth Thompson St. Leger d'Happart to d'Happart, 1803-1805 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Elizabeth Thompson St. Leger d'Happart to d'Happart, 1803-1805 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Henriette de St. Leger to d'Happart, 1805-1814 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Henriette de St. Leger to d'Happart, 1805-1814 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Henriette de St. Leger to d'Happart, 1805-1814 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Henriette de St. Leger to d'Happart, 1805-1814 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Henriette de St. Leger to d'Happart, 1805-1814 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Divorce and Estrangement from Elizabeth Thompson St. Leger d'Happart, 1812-1815 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Divorce and Estrangement from Elizabeth Thompson St. Leger d'Happart, 1812-1815 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Divorce and Estrangement from Elizabeth Thompson St. Leger d'Happart, 1812-1815 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Oration given by d'Happart, July 4, 1814 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Receipt wallet, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Receipt wallet contents, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Transcription books, VII.
  These bound transcription books contain handwritten copies of correspondence in English and French. They seem to be correspondence to and from d'Happart and his family. These books appear to be the work of a nineteenth century family member. Please note that the inclusive dates given for each transcription book represent the letters on the first and last page of that volume; the letters within each book are not in strict chronological order, so the dates are primarily for the identification of individual books. These transcription books are not comprehensive, and include family correspondence not contained in their original form elsewhere in this collection.
  - Transcription book, March 20, 1800-June 17, 1800 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Transcription book, August 25, 1800-July 1801 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Transcription book, 1800-1808 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Transcription book, March 6, 1802-June 28-1802 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Transcription book, October 25, 1802-April 10, 1803 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Transcription book, March 19, 1805-September 3, 1805 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Transcription book, 1805-1807 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Transcription book, 1808 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Transcription book, December 5, 1808-January 11, 1809 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Transcription book, 1808-1810 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Transcription book, January 14, 1809-Febraury 20, 1810 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Transcription book, 1810 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Transcription book, 1811-1812 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Transcription book, June 14, 1815-September 18, 1815 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Transcription book, January 2, 1806-January 13, 1815 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Transcription book, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Transcription book, 1801-1802 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Published materials, VIII.
  These published materials were likely collected by d'Happart in the United States and France. They include literary magazines published in the United States in English and French, and two longer French language works.
  - Hemisphere, October 21, 1809 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Hemisphere, December 30, 1809 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Hemisphere, January 13, 1810 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Hemisphere, September 1, 1810 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - L'Abeille, no. 20, February 27, 1817 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Historiques, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Nouveaux Contes Moraux, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - The Portfolio, vol. viii, July 1819 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The Portfolio, vol. viii, December 1825 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Calendar Cards, IX.
  These index cards were created by a twentieth century researcher who used the Joseph d'Happart papers. Each card summarizes a document, and references the document by date. This collection of cards is not exhaustive; not all documents in the collection are represented by a card. The creator of the cards evidently did not speak French, supplying no summary of French language documents, instead simply identifying that they are written "in French."
  - Calendar Cards (Box 17)